I think the concept of vibe coding makes
no sense. I'm just going to type stuff
into an agent and what comes out is like
what comes out. It's still software
engineering. You're still designing
systems, writing specs, making sure the
tests are good, code reviewing, so our
customers are dev. So we think a lot
about what's changing in how they build
software. Are there new developers? Do
the new developers have different sort
of needs? Can we use new technology?
This isn't new to AI. It's like any kind
of technology. And so Centry has a ton
of data. And what we do is we
effectively compress and summarize a lot
of that data, feed it into an LLM. that
OL has a bunch of tools similar to all
these agents like read source code and
then can it come up with an analysis of
this using those tools and that data
we're able to feed it in there. I would
say historically we have a moat in the
sense of we have so much interconnected
data about the application itself
whereas a lot of other vendors that do
application monitoring they operate at a
different level.
>> You haven't written code by hand in the
last 6 weeks but you're shipping
production systems on it. What is your
development process look like right now?
So first I want to start with a very
important concept.
[Music]
Hello everyone. Welcome back to the AI
native dev. Thanks for tuning back in.
Uh today we'll have a fun conversation
that talks about developing with AI from
these sort of two angles. One is from a
um slightly I don't know if it's
contrarian or you know pioneering
perspective of how to build with AI. uh
and the other is from building tools
into AI which I guess is also a
pioneering frontier in its own right and
to cover all of those or talk about
those uh we have with us David Kramer
who's probably best known as the
co-founder of Sentry which is tool I've
always uh very much sort of appreciate a
lot of the Devex sensibilities and
usefulness of it uh and with some sort
of deep developer background prior to
that. Uh David thanks for coming on to
the show. Yeah. Yeah. Thanks for having
me. Looking forward just u.
>> So maybe just to get us started, can you
give us a little bit of background about
uh about yourself and then maybe about
Sentry just mostly from from the context
of this is the world in which you're
experimenting with AI and so um you know
how uh what is it that you're uh
learning all around you?
>> Yeah, we've got a I and and we as in
Century have a pretty wide breath of
concern. So like obviously there's um
century is a dev tool and so our
customers are devs so we think a lot
about you know what's changing in how
they build software are there new
developers do the new developers have
different sort of needs um right now I
would say not really um but then there's
also the angle of like can we use new
technology this isn't new to AI it's
like any kind of technology ship but
like can we use it to build new or
different software and there's also sort
of like the green field of like should
we be building something completely new
that's not just like sort of
incrementally adding to century software
and then I think like the last piece
which has probably been the more
interesting topical piece as of you know
the recent months which is like how does
it actually change your job like how can
you leverage a technology to say you
know higher shipping velocity or
something of that nature and I
personally spent a lot of time on that
front of like um sort of exploring the
tools like I'm not an academic by any
means I'm like a self-taught software
engineer but I think of myself as a
really good applied engineer in the
sense of like I don't know anything
about the academics. I roughly know like
what a markoff chain is. Um
but I'm very very good at like debugging
software and like figuring out how
things work and and so I've just spent a
lot of time like really in the weeds of
like okay like
>> how can you push this and use it to the
the maximum effectiveness which to be
fair is like the same way you would
learn how you might apply it to like say
your product or a new product or
something of that nature.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Which is it's the
practitioner view, right? you're sort of
learning by doing and uh uh and you're
bringing in the the competency, right?
Like I think in software we often times
um there's a blending of the world of
like I'm building dev tools and I'm
using dev tools which is actually like a
privilege that we have that we often
forget is a privilege. Uh you know when
you're whatever building tools for
lawyers you know often times people
building it are not lawyers themselves
and so there's this split here. So it
sort of things like you're you're coming
in from the practitioner perspective,
you have some subject matter, maybe you
have a little bit less familiarity with
the underpinnings of how the uh how the
uh the AI math uh operates. Uh but you
see it in practice. So I guess I guess
in that in that context um uh we have
this two topics here to to cover. one is
uh just sort of understand a little bit
with that sort of sentry lens uh what it
is that you are building uh as you're
kind of experimenting with bringing
value uh to your user base you know or
like using LLM to do so and then the
other lens is just you've been doing
some really interesting things around
how you build software yourself and how
you uh minimize uh the uh the manual
typing of uh of that coding um maybe
maybe we start a little bit with the
sentry side just so that we can relate
then your practices as to maybe things
that you've built. Can you tell us a
couple of interesting things you've
built?
Appreciating these are all kind of early
stage or like you know a fastmoving uh
changes but that seem useful around how
do you apply LLM to Sentry to make it
better for its users.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So I think the first thing
we built which is actually time is
fuzzy. First we had co and now we have
like this AI thing where like it's moved
pretty fast. Um, so I don't know, call
it a year ago, we took embeddings. And
so Century's core technology, it isn't
much. It's like we're a big big enough
company these days, so it's not that
simple, but if you try to simplify as
much as possible, we capture errors. We
put them in a dashboard, and then we do
a bunch of like sort of processing in
between those phases. And one of the
things we do that's really critical is
dduplication. And that comes from what
we call fingerprinting which generally
is like a lot of regular expressions or
something equivalent to regular
expressions historically. And one thing
we found pretty early with embeddings
you know so you know adjacent was we
could actually improve our dduplication
with embeddings quite drastically. And
so for example, the way a lot of this
works is like you'll you'll go into like
a programming language. Take Ruby and
Ruby will have anonymous functions in
the programming language and they have
like random integers inserted into the
function names or something like this.
It's been a while so it might have
changed but this is what I recall. And
so you end up writing a lot of these
rules that parse those things out so
they actually match together because
they have to be static. embeddings
actually let you get much closer, you
know, from uh uh I guess lower total
work. Um and they're not enough on their
own for what it's worth, but um so we
applied that and and saw like massive
improvements early on and we're like
okay that's cool and that's how we think
about it for what it's worth. It's not
like oh what's the cool gimmick we're
like we are a real business that is like
going to sustain and we want like real
applications and so that was a great
early application more recently and the
thing that actually impressed me
>> and so we're like okay how do we apply
LM and in our space generally speaking
in dev tools I think the most exciting
thing about LLMs is just like code
generation right because like if you can
generate code and understand code
there's a lot of really interesting
things and that's one area that is like
basically not approachable before
whereas like fingerprinting yeah we
could solve it forever it's just a lot
of tedious work. Code generation, not a
chance, you know. Um, and so early on
we're like, okay, what's adjacent to
Century that we could apply this tech
to? And we were like, okay, what if we
could actually sort of automatically fix
bugs or automatically generate tests or
something along those lines, right? And
let me preface this with you can't
reliably do that today. So, this is more
of like what if we can get there, which
is really important. I think that's the
way the and so we started building
something in the space and the thesis
was Century has a lot of data. I would
say historically we have a moat in the
sense of like we have so much
interconnected data about the
application itself whereas a lot of
other vendors that do sort of
application monitoring they operate like
at a different level they operate like
at the system level or something it's
just not
>> the data is just kind of junk if you
ever looked at like like something like
Splunk or like a log aggregator and you
look through the logs you understand
what I mean dump all the data in as
opposed to some form of qualification
proper curation of it. Yeah. And ours is
like highly structured, highly semantic.
And we're like, you know what? Let's try
like interlinking all this data, which
this is prel to be fair. And so we we
made this trace connected data set. And
then we're like, you know what, I wonder
like if we could throw this into LMS
because they're it's effectively pattern
matching um and they do a really good
job at large scales of data. What would
come out of it? Like how well could it
help us diagnose things? And we're
building this actually for probably the
better part of the last year we've been
working on this. And this is our thing
called Seir. S E R if you've seen it.
But
>> I remember a few months back I'm like,
can we ship this yet? It's been so long.
And I'm like, it probably doesn't work
still because if you've used any of
these tools, they like just make up like
they hallucinate, if you will. Um
because they just don't have the right
information. And so I remember going in
and there was a JavaScript bug on one of
my side projects. And I'm like, look,
let me show you why this technology is a
problem. It's not going to be able to
understand what's going on here no
matter what. Like I can't understand it.
I'm an expert in this and I run the
thing. It gives me some like really
wacky root cause and that's the main
thing it does is root cause analysis,
not patch generation. The patch
generation is whatever. Um, but it comes
up with root cause. The root cause makes
no sense to me. And I show it to the
team. I'm like, look, look, this is
completely wrong. This is why it's not
ready. The next day, somebody at our
company is like, okay, I hit this bug.
And they show me like the actual error.
And I don't remember exactly the
details, but I'm like, oh, that's like
that's what it said the problem was. And
like it was actually right. And I was
genuinely impressed because what I will
tell my my singular belief is the reason
an engineer is valuable. Like go to like
a big company like a Google and you have
these staff principal engineers that get
paid lots of money. A lot of times
they're not doing that much in terms of
actual outputs. And for a long time in
my career I'm like well what's the like
why? It doesn't make any sense you know.
Um and I have a lot of friends that had
these jobs and they're very cushy. And
then I I eventually came to reason about
like the value of that is their
knowledge of the system and their
ability to like theory craft around
what's going on and thus to debug the
system very very fast. Um and this can
actually do that pretty well. I was like
genuinely shocked. And so we spent a
bunch of time building this. We're still
working on it. Um it's still super
early. Like just like all these things,
it doesn't work that well. Um but when
it works it, you know,
>> I I I think uh so so I love the the
notion of like uh digesting substantial
volumes of data. uh especially when you
have it and you have it well structured
on it is is is I think like a superpower
that's sort of been acknowledged uh and
you're right that one problem is
hallucinations like it will give you an
answer even if it is making it up uh
pretty uh creatively um another problem
is uh is kind of managing the context
window right of like how which bits of
the data do you deliver right to uh to
uh uh to be analyzed on it um I don't
know like was was that problem an issue?
I guess in general what were the
obstacles to getting it to to work? And
do you have any insights on almost like
um uh the uh the the practices or the
methodologies that you think it's the
same skills that sort of help to build
or make this product uh actually
effective uh versus which are new skills
that you know people on the team needed
to to build up. Honestly, I think a lot
of the skills are the same. Like there
there was this era early LLM.
So the industry has always been this
way. There's academia and then there's
the real world is how I would describe
it. And I remember uh the era of NoSQL
databases where academia was always
present. It's like oh maybe we found a
new way to scale databases and it would
never work. It could never work in
practice because systems are really
large and really complex and
infrastructure is hard etc. Um that's
the same right now. And so when this all
started it was mostly like data
scientists like building with LMS and
there were DAGs and all these
complicated workflows and then very
quickly it it started to evolve and now
we for example the common pattern today
is an agent which is just a service we
just renamed service to agent for some
reason um and it has a bunch of tool
calls which are just RPC calls you know
to something whether it's internal RPC
or external RPC and I actually think we
are still a little bit legacy with our
workflow for this. it might still be
like a an effectively like a pipeline or
whatever you whatever these early terms
were looks more like a a DAG uh a graph
call um but generally speaking it's a
lot of like the way I always articulate
the best way you can leverage technology
today and I think this is important
because like if you listen to this a
year from now who knows
>> it's like map reduce so it's like you
have a lot of information can you
compress it in a way that isn't losing
the most vital parts
>> and then can you repeat that process
until you get the outcome you need and
so century has a ton of data and What we
do is we effectively compress and
summarize a lot of that data, feed it
into an LLM. That LM has a bunch of
tools similar to all these agents,
right? Like read source code. I don't
actually remember what else is in there,
but that was really important. Um, and
then can it come up with an analysis of
this? You know, using those tools and
and sort of that data, we're able to
feed it in there. And from there, and I
think this is true with everything you
try to do these days, it becomes like
questionably scientific in the sense of
you're like, does this kind of look
better? Does this seem like it would be
better? like it it's there's just it's
it's so non-deterministic that it's
actually really painful to work with
when you're trying to improve it. And
obviously we have things like eval that
help, but it's it's still I feel like
it's still just like you're mostly
banking on model improvements at the end
of the day and and the tool chain being
effective of course like that is really
really important and the data being like
high quality and um high signal and
stuff but but it is a lot on the model
ultimately
>> on the yeah I do find it um entertaining
where on one hand like what has evolved
substantially is these calculations of
massive numbers and math to really
really encode data and a very
mathematical, very precise way to create
these massive models and like spend
billions of dollars training them. On
the other side, you have vibe coding uh
and h yeah it looks right. I'm going to
ship it. I can build this feature. So
maybe maybe this is a good time to to
shift a little bit. So thanks for the
taste of it of some of the uh learnings
and opportunities that you're seeing in
Sentry to uh bring kind of LLM powers to
the forefront. I'm sure there there's
many more. Let's talk a little bit about
your uh development flow. So when we
spoke before you kind of gave me the
statement that says uh that you haven't
written code by hand in the last 6 weeks
but you're shipping production uh
systems on it. Um maybe take us a bit
into this world like what uh what does
your development process look like right
now and maybe maybe some of the early
learnings uh from uh um how it changed.
>> First I want to start with a a very
important concept. I think the concept
of vibe coding makes no sense. It's like
this idea of like yolo, if you will.
Like there's this whole thing of like
I'm just going to type stuff into an
agent and like what comes out is like
what comes out. It's still software
engineering. You're still designing
systems, writing specs, making sure the
tests are good, code reviewing all this
stuff. So I think that's really really
important to understand. But um and
unfortunately I did have to write code
like what day of the week is a couple
days ago because I couldn't get it to do
the thing I needed. Yeah.
>> Version now of uh how long how many days
have you gone without writing code? This
was uh about eight weeks before I had to
do it. And I spent like four days and
and just so everybody understands my
full-time job is not really writing code
even though I I actually do a little bit
more for the company now. It's more like
passion projects. So even on MCP
service, which is a thing that I built
and maintaining,
it's very valuable to the company right
now, but it is effectively a side
project. Um and it's a side project I'm
helping maintain. Um but that the the
MCP service I wrote it by hand on that
particularly I like systems don't change
software doesn't really change at the
end of the day and so if you can reason
about how just software works everything
looks pretty similar so MCP I'm like
okay it's a plug-in architecture it's
how you integrate it's a little bit of a
flipped funnel it's like I can build the
integration and stick it anywhere or a
customer can stick it anywhere which is
like not typical when you think about
cloud service integrations and things
like that it to be clear it has a lot of
use cases I'm very focused on how it
applies to Sentry Um but and so as soon
as they announced like the oath spec I'm
like okay I could extract value out of
this now I can insert century in the
cursor in cloud code or something like
that and it's very very high value and
so as soon as that happened I I quickly
whipped up a prototype that cloud flare
was was uh working on some MVP stuff as
well. We pulled that in and I I don't
know within a couple days we had
something production ready or not. It's
it's questionable these days. What is
production ready? But it was working
totally fine. And so I spent a bunch of
time working on that. And and if you use
that too, definitely check it out. Um it
is you can just drop in a link to a
century issue. It'll pull in the right
context. If you use Seir, it'll pull in
Sears context as well. And the workflow
is like it's really really really good.
And so it's a great experience. But when
we think about it that way, it's not
like we built an a random Sentry
everywhere integration. It's like no, I
built a thing that makes it highly
functional to use Sentry inside of
coding agents, right?
>> And it just happens to be an abstract
protocol. And so that's how we think
about the product. Um
>> it's effectively middleware, right? Sort
of it's it's middleware.
>> It's kind of like middleware. Yeah.
because you needed the API you needed
the sentry APIs to begin with uh to
provide multiple services and then you
have the client that already runs and
you're creating an intim layer that that
does the LLM world translation of here
are here's some information client about
when would you use me and here's a a
means of converting that into the proper
API call uh and maybe in the back end
>> I would say that's high level but it
goes deeper like I'll give you an
analogy um MCP actually has two agents
embedded inside of it. And so a bunch of
the MCP call tool calls are just like
roughly translate this input to one or
more API calls and then translate that
output into one response. Um but now
there's a couple search endpoints that
exist inside of it. So like find errors
or or run um so Century does more than
errors. It does logs and traces and all
this stuff. And within logs and traces
particularly you have a bunch of
attributes. You might want to run
functions on those aggregations ask
questions. Oh, here's a really good
analogy in the MC in in claude or uh
cursor. I can say what was the total
token consumption of X service yesterday
and it can answer that through centuries
MCP call and that's not just like
mapping that to like an API call. That's
actually mapping that to a natural
language input that then gets thrown
inside of another agent that then gets
mapped to API calls if that makes sense.
So it's I would say yes it's middleware.
I mean everything's middleware. Um, but
you can actually go a lot deeper if you
really think about the product
experience. And so that's where it gets
interesting. And honestly, I think the
future of a lot of this is just this
like um it's like the embedded agents or
agent to agent communication because
it's still a lot of natural language
stuff. It's still non-deterministic. You
can't expect it to randomly write the
write API calls, you know. So, um, but
we spent a lot of time on that and
particularly this is why I ran the
experiment of like could I not write
code by hand ever again? And that was a
lot of time like can I like colllocate
the right documentation? Can I write the
right context prompts? Can I can I get
all all this stuff that will probably
improve the system based on how the
technology works? The answer is like yes
and no. Um sometimes it'll impress you
and then other times you're like dude
just ignore everything. Um
>> and then so like it was a really fun
experiment and
>> we're we're not there yet is what I
would say. But but the techn is really
interesting. I I would I would encourage
everyone to try an exercise like this if
they can. Like one thing I will say is
like it will slow you down a lot of
times doing it this way and you should
not think about doing it this way in
like real world critical software like
for centuries core codebased you do not
write code through agents and only
agents kind of thing like you might run
an agent to generate a test or an API
and then going to go review tweak that
thing and that's that's still a big
performance improvement or to debug
something big performance improvement. M
this is like I can take it off, go to a
meeting, come back,
>> maybe I've got a starting thing to run
with, you know. So I I don't know. But
but either way, it's a useful exercise
to learn the limitations of where we are
today and to learn how you might improve
upon those limitations because that
latter part that's where I would
absolutely bet is going to stay true
again because like software is pretty
reliable. There's no magic in any of
this. Like the the way systems improve
generally stays the same over time. um
they just get easier to improve or maybe
need less of this kind of behavior. And
so um but it has been a good learning
experience.
>> Yeah. And first of all, it sounds we've
actually done a couple of those versions
uh here in Tesla. We sort of picked a
couple of topics in which we build
entirely agentic workflows, not to
create the code, but actually systems
that run entirely agentically uh as we
assess software to create specs from it
and and and the likes. Uh and it's been
it's been, you know, it's bittersweet,
you know, you you learn it. Um I guess
what are some of the key
um uh maybe I don't know if it's a
learnings or sort of insights right
you're coming into this experiment
coming out eight weeks later like uh
there's sort of two questions in my mind
one is what do you believe now that you
didn't believe before right some
conviction you've acquired uh and two is
uh what what did your job look like uh
during that time what were the primary
things you did create by hand that you
got better at uh over the course these
weeks.
>> I think importantly like the workflow
just to understand what this looks like
is
you kind of start like I want to solve a
problem. Maybe you've got a ticket or
something like this and you really need
to kind of get it down to like a really
lightweight spec of some sorts. I I I
don't write anything to be clear. Like
this is all generated 100% of this. So
it's like even the spec is me describing
and refining it. Like actually think of
like uh center. It's like, you know,
we're like uh I forget what they call
themselves, but you're sitting here just
prompting over and over trying to refine
the thing, right? But doing it through
human language, which sometimes is
ineffective. And so I do that first and
then I get into implementation.
Um and then usually what you find a lot
of the time is it will do okay. And it
really depends on the task for what it's
worth. And it's not even about the size
of the task. And this is you find a lot
of like just FUD on the internet. It's
just like people who don't actually
build software, don't know what the
they're talking about, frankly. It's not
about the size of the task or any of
this It's about sort of the
complexity in the task based on the
commonality of the task. And so like
again, it's a it's an effectively it's
pattern matching. And so it's like if if
you're doing something that can't easily
find like common patterns where this
lives next to this all the time, it just
doesn't actually know what to do. So
it's going to reach for another common
pattern that looks like that. And and so
you'll find like a really good example
where it went off the rails is when I
started doing these embedded agents
inside of the tools. It's an MCP tool.
Calling an agent, calling other tools.
Good luck ever getting on the guard
rails, you know, because it's just it
gets so lost in
>> words, right? Which it is a confusing
thing. I'm like, which tool is which,
you know, right?
>> And no matter how you try to steer it,
it always ends up getting lost again
because it it's it's it's a very lossy
compression at the end of the day.
>> Yeah. Which interestingly is like it's a
human problem as well, right? If you
were to say you're calling this thing
and you're using the word agent, you
know, in
>> uh the newest fashion of it, you don't
know what's going to happen.
>> Yeah. And it doesn't help. And and and
what I would tell you is again, it's not
simple versus complex. The
implementation is unbelievably simple.
And I can give it a full spec of exactly
the architecture of how this works. It's
really easy to reason about. It's it's
not it's just a chain of function calls
>> and it would just still go way off the
rails. And then and then you get in
these cycles where you try to get it to
fix itself. And then my my favorite
analogy I give people and this is a very
good example of how you cannot control
it with context management is
immediately when something goes wrong it
will try to insert the any type in
Typescript all the time. No matter how
much you guard rail against using the
any type and so I have it in like in the
cloud envy at the top of it in the
prompts like critical don't use this.
And if you if you send that in every
prompt, it's probably okay, but you
don't that's not how you work, right?
>> Um, and that's that I think that happens
because of how common that is in the
training data set. But again, I'm not an
academic, so I don't know. Um, but
either way, it goes off the rails and
then you sit here fighting with it. And
this is the problem. This is where you
waste time and you shouldn't rely on
like pure agent development because like
you are going to spend way more time
trying to refine that thing through
prompts than you would just opening the
editor. And so I think alian that's not
like a it's kind of obvious that would
be true, but you don't really know how
frequently it's going to break. I would
bet sub 10% of the time was I able to
get like a one shot fix in, you know,
without like serious refinement. And and
even sub 10% where like one or two
prompts got it correct. It was it's
usually like 20 prompts to get something
even remotely good. And again, this is
this is real world software. I'm not
just generating junk. I needed to be
maintainable, testable. Um,
>> and then if you don't review it, it's
even worse because it will just in like
I there was one I didn't review and I
thought I I did cuz I usually skim this
stuff whereas having it generated on
side projects. So there isn't uh there
isn't like a mandate of uh or like this
like this a specific project and so it's
not a uh the team won't review it if you
don't necessarily. kind of yeah we don't
have the same controls on this so we
don't require the team to review it
>> but even so humans make mistake too
right like so I actually review the code
but you know it's like I review the code
and I'm not going line by line of
everything um and there was one where I
had to build an integration test and I
thought I had reviewed it and made sure
it was doing what I wanted to and I went
back to it and I found it was like
inserting something random that was
basically it was not testing what I
wanted it to test at all you know and it
was fine like the the there were other
things that checked this But that's
that's one of the fundamental problems.
And so what I learned through this was
and again this is like what you should
know but there is like a very real thing
like don't be a pessimist is I think a
really good rule. You need to kind of
like don't just assume truth in things
but you need to live some of these
experiences. And so like part of this
was me. I'm like I'm going to try out
cloud code. You know it's a terminal
based UI. I don't know how well it's
going to work. It's very impressive to
be to be clear. Cloud code is like
phenomenal as software.
>> Yeah. But I think my biggest learning
and something that a lot of the internet
will be like no no no you don't know
what you're doing is like cloud code is
actually not a great like this is the
wrong user interface for where we are
with this stage of technology and what I
mean by this is if I use cursor ignoring
the agent differences because at the end
of the day the model is the main thing
that's making the biggest impact. So the
agents are close enough to the same. If
I use cursor and I run through their
agent and I I generate a change set in
real time I'm getting the diffs in my
editor. I'm able to approve blocks of
code really seamlessly. I'm able to jump
between these files really seamlessly.
If I'm using cloud code, I've got this
like endless terminal slog. Yes, I can
manually approve every single change and
review it right there, but it is not
easy to review it right there. You're
viewing like code editions, not not the
actual source code and things like this.
And and so my biggest I think point of
view is like that is that is wrong.
That's not the right customer exper like
that is not a good product right now in
terms of how it needs to be used by
developers in real world software. I
think cursor is a much better experience
for this kind of thing.
So what's the I I love the perspective
of it and I I don't necessarily disagree
like I find this is like a learning uh
exercise right now. I guess if you cast
your eyes further there's a claim that
says well cloud code needs to get better
at explaining the changes that it has
done because of this constraint of
working through the terminal. And so,
you know, is it is it in a place in
which it would uh uh improve its ability
to uh engage with you without needing to
review the code changes because of this
interface or or does it I guess another
lens is that it just commoditizes the
idea. You don't really care if it's
cursor or the other. You just need some
sort of lightweight integrations into
the surrounding. Do those resonate or do
these come back to like no no this this
like there's a couple of years here at
least or a few years in which you're
going to need to look at all the
changes?
>> I I think you're going to look at all
the changes forever. I don't think this
technology is enabling AGI or any of
these these things that people are
spewing on the internet. They're not
removing engineers. I spend as much if
not more time doing actual engineering
work than ever before with this
technology because I am still designing
a system like these things aren't
intelligent. they're just spitting out
patterns, right? And
ignoring the academics because who
cares? It's about like real life what
these are and what they're producing.
And so, and again, this is why I find
the cursor flow so much more superior
because I do actually have to review the
code. And if I can incrementally review
it as it's going through and I can
interrupt and do all these things, I
think that's important. Like I'll tell
you, we when when I was hiring our CTO,
one of these things you do when you hire
executives is you usually have them give
some kind of like pitch or like like go
through a deck of some random
shenanigans. probably done this with
with folks you've hired.
>> And I'm like, I hate this because
they're always so just
>> useless basically. And so I'm like, you
know what I want them to do? Because I
still want to understand, can they
storytell? Can can they engage in stuff?
And and so these things you test, I'm
like, I want them to just give a pitch
on something that they're interested in,
like a short presentation, a Q&A and
stuff. And our CTO previously worked at
Apple for a period of time on the
autonomous car division. And and he was
interest or at least wanted to do it on
on just self-driving cars. And I'm like,
that's cool. nothing new entry. I don't
care.
>> Yeah, definitely cool though. And one
sav I super agree with is the problem
right now is everybody and and sort of
maybe his take was Apple did this wrong
is like they just wanted to go full
self-driving all the way to automation
which you see this in the LM too like
everybody's like wants to believe that
agents can just run on their own and the
right answer is like humans should be in
the loop and I think cursor's user
experience for example is a much better
version of humans in the loop because I
incrementally review things so the
context for me is smaller you know I
have it in the surrounding context I can
see the source code
I understand. I don't build software
through a blog in the terminal. Like it
just it just doesn't make a lot of sense
to use things that way except if you had
full autonomy, which I just don't see.
>> Yeah.
>> Like I don't see the technology we have
today getting to full autonomy by any
and it could. Who knows? Like that's the
academic part. Maybe it can get there. I
don't think they know either to be
clear. But um
>> yeah,
>> and I think that's really important
though. It's like you you can't pretend
these things can do things they can't do
and you need a human in the loop and
it's like well what's the best
experience if you have to have a human
in the loop to me it's not generate a
bunch of stuff then go to GitHub and
review it and then go back and refine it
over and over and to me it's not have it
running in a terminal over here and have
the editor over here and then click
around file you know I just they're not
they're high friction experiences
>> I I uh super interesting and I guess
again like maybe back to the uh we're
all experimenting here nobody knows on
it I do wonder about uh the definition
of the guardrails. So I guess in uh in
in in Tesla like there's a bunch of
words you were doing that made me
tempted to sort of mention Tesla uh uh
in those where you're saying you know
you write a spec at the beginning on it
like clearly that's like our core
premise is that should be your sort of
the the primary artifact uh uh in your
uh in your project and actually we have
these uh kind of levels of autonomy
levels of a unit of software uh and
modeled after self-driving cars and and
thinking about sort of the five levels
of of autonomy U so we'll kind of write
that up and and publish it soon enough.
But within within that context, one of
the premises is well one of the things
that would make you not need to review
it uh is if you have good tests. And so
if your definitions for the things that
you've built uh are uh covered or sort
of you know backed by tests and you
trust the tests which by the way don't
get in the way of the IDE commentary.
That's a different place of a human in
the loop. Uh but once you've defined
those then to those you don't really
need to get back. Um and I guess I'm I'm
curious on you know whether that
resonates and whether uh I guess how how
did your kind of relationship with tests
uh uh change or play a role as you were
sort of avoiding the coding? Was it like
I'm trying to get you to understand
something that I'm doing here? Uh and
the way to convey that is this test
needs to pass.
>> Yeah. I mean my rule was I cannot use I
cannot edit the code myself. So it's
quite complicated. I'm a big test guy.
I'm not I don't do TDD if you will. That
is like I don't write the test before
writing the code, but I don't test the
code manually ever if I can avoid it.
And this is my entire career. I I refuse
to manually test code if I can avoid it.
And then we are in the reality where UI
is ever present and UI is more code than
ever and good luck kind of thing. It's
like a real problem. If you've ever
worked in JavaScript like you cannot
test things like end to end is
impossible. It's like really really
difficult to get it working. Test
harnesses are hard. Most people don't
actually test things in an effective
way. Um, and so I do have a bunch of
tests. I I've even written like um if
you use TDScript in V test um I wrote an
evals adapter that just implements an
eval spec but does it through the test
because I need CI to do CI like that
again technology doesn't change. We
still need the same validation layer but
I'm like okay I need it to generate the
test and what I will tell you what's
really impressive if you can get a
really simple system. And so I'm using
this technology called ORPC which is
like um it's like a JavaScript API
binding layer like a server side thing
that also has a client side binding but
that doesn't matter but the server side
is so easy to reason about as a human
and as a machine of course because if
it's easy for a human it's easy for a
machine to pattern match against it. Um
>> I was able to code generate an entire
migration from one technology to the
other because the API is so simple to
reason about
>> and I was able to generate tests for
that and it was able to validate
everything because everything was
simple. it was clear. It was not a lot
of boiler plate. And I think that's a
really important concept because what I
think happens over the next few years,
fingers crossed because we need this is
a lot of this complexity goes away and
we we return to spending time solving
real problems because a lot of what's
happened in my industry, which I live in
this JavaScript world these days, Yeah.
>> it's just infinite complexity. I don't
see the value gain we've gotten as a as
an industry out of it. I don't see
better software, more reliable software,
faster to ship software. I see more
complicated software, things that are
not common place being like front and
center, right? And I I see people not
writing tests. I see people not
understanding core systems design. And I
got to believe this is going to
reconcile that because again, there's no
magic in these. The simpler the sort of
technology stack that they're working
with, the better it is for humans, the
easier for us to write code, the easier
it's going to be for them to debug, to
to build all this stuff. And so I I'm
very hopeful that this just implicitly
creates more value in that just like
it's implicitly creating more value in
specs in documentation and stuff which
despite what people would like to
believe are actually not that valuable
to humans because we we learn context
and retain it really really well. So you
go to a new codebase. Yeah. You might
read some onboarding docs. You're not
going back to the docs ever. You don't
need to read them ever again. You just
look at the code and you know what's
going on. Yeah. Yeah. But like the docs
are actually super valuable to the LMS
because they don't retain context, you
know, and and so it it's just really
interesting how the the same things that
have always been sort of important to
software design or at least as important
now, if not more important,
>> right? Yeah. No, I love that. I I guess
I love both of those points. One is this
notion of retaining context versus not
like agents know they they retain
context. They're also more disciplined
in that sense, which is, you know, they
uh there's all these sort of running
jokes of like, you know, we wouldn't
write docs for our teammates, but we do
for the agents. And, you know, the
obvious reply being, "Yeah, because the
agents actually read them." uh and but
but uh but beyond the sort of the snarky
uh version of it, you make a good point
which is like as humans we uh were maybe
better at remembering the things that
are salient uh while thems and the other
the other is this notion of adaptability
you know I think a lot about adaptable
software uh and I think your point
around JavaScript and the mess is like
much of that is because of the
interweaving of the implementation
details and know browsers changing over
time and all these subtleties and
supporting the sort of infinite sort of
uh stream of of historical ones. Um, and
and you know, over overcoming the
natural way that browsers evolve is they
see these quirky patterns and then they
create a new way to make it simple and
make it clean. But then you have all
these historical websites that uh that
do not have that. And so um it it it's
nice to think that it did that higher
level abstraction uh into natural
language will will reduce that because
LLMs can provide adaptability.
I'd love to uh take it a little bit into
uh into the the the broader team and
maybe ecosystem you know in our sort of
last 10ish minutes here um and just talk
so so you you know you've you've you've
taken the plunge right you've sort of uh
uh sub subjected yourself to these sort
of uh eight weeks of uh non-coding and
um and uh and building with it uh and
you know you have a bunch of these
learnings around you know how do you
interact with them what what is it if
you think uh today and tomorrow which of
these practices would you recommend and
you're probably not just recommending
but like actually driving the broader
Sentry development team uh would use and
I'm using that really as a proxy of
course for dev team today uh to build
what should they do let's let's split
those up is like what should uh do you
want to see the entire team do today and
then we'll talk about you know what do
you think tomorrow
>> yeah well okay so I think the first
problem is this is unrelated to century
because we've solved this you need to
able to use these tools and you really
need your workplace to enable
consumption of these tools. Like a month
or something ago, I took away compliance
on IP at Century in the sense of
>> we no longer consider source code
protected.
>> Like that doesn't mean we won't enforce
our license. I I will come after you if
you steal our code to be clear. Um but
what I mean is like
>> I don't care if say cursor accidentally
up and leaks our source code.
Well, what it's already public whatever
we don't care. But I'm also not worried
about I'm not saying cursor would ever
do this to be clear, but but
>> some people will as we've already seen
this in the industry. I'm not worried
about them training on our data. I'm not
gonna necessarily say they can, but if
they do the shenanigan that some of the
model providers are doing where they're
like, we're just going to ask for
forgiveness later, we don't consider
that a risk to the business anymore.
>> And that was a 24-hour decision that I
just made that was really, really
important to the company because
instantly it allowed us to adopt a bunch
of tools.
>> Not everybody can do that. So that's
hard, but you need to really have a
workplace that can enable these or
you're paying out of pocket quite a lot,
which I also do um to do these on your
side projects, but you need to be able
to use them. I think and that's the
first and foremost thing. And so,
>> and that is what I'm pushing
essentially. I like I did this and I'm
like, folks, tell me what tools you
want. I'm not going to give most of them
to you because they're garbage and they
don't solve problems and you can't just
have infinite tools and customer data is
still a separate concern. Um, but you
need to use the tools. And so we gave
access the cloud code and cursor to
everybody in the company. we give chat
to everybody in the company. There's
probably some other valuable tools, but
it's about like most bang for your buck,
but what's most important to start
learning? Um, and so I think that's
number one. Beyond that, this has been
hard. So, the biggest challenge you'll
face is this archetype of like um a
senior engineer that's maybe not
pessimistic, but roughly pessimistic
that tries one of the Yeah, cynical.
Cynical is the better word. And I am
this to be clear. They open a a prompt,
they type something, and it produces
garbage. And they're like, "See, it
doesn't work, you know,
>> and yes, it doesn't work."
>> Yeah.
>> And and despite what anybody wants to
believe, it will not work that way. And
so, you got to get past and you got to
force people past that point. Be like,
"Yes, it's not going to work." This is
how you make it work. And that needs to
be like a self-feeding cycle of
everybody teaching each other because
the name of the game is just to give it
all the information it needs to succeed.
And I like to explain this to people,
which is like if you don't tell it the
facts, it will not be able to answer the
question. You have to give it the answer
right then and there. and and then
you'll look at you like that makes no
sense then why don't I do the work
myself and it's like well what you're
giving it is like the page from the docs
or something it's like you're not
actually writing that or giving it that
but like here's the UI go fetch it and
then don't do the thing right you have
to still feed it all of this information
to set it up for success and that's
something yes that's obvious if you just
reason about how the thing works but
also you just like like very quickly
come to understand as you try to use it
too and then you see wildly different
results and so I think it's really like
use it as much as possible, really learn
how like what kinds of context it needs
and how to pass it in and then find ways
to do that. So a really cool experiment
we've been uh running down is like can
we expose all our docs in a useful way.
So there's this MCP provider that I
think is really interesting called
context 7. I haven't used it but what it
does is take a bunch of like I think
roughly open source products and stuff
and expose the docs over MCP because you
can't just like these things don't know
software. They don't know the random
things you're using. and they don't know
the APIs. They're just guessing and
that's what people don't understand.
It's just pattern matching and you
actually have to feed it the right docs
for the right library. And sometimes
it'll look in the source code or
whatever. But um so we've we've taken
our public doc. So century
docs.entry.io.
We've generated markdown files. They're
sort of um cleaned up. And so it's like
we generate a markdown file for every
single page that's at like a dedicated
URL that gets rid of a lot of the layout
stuff. It gets rid of some other
elements. And you can think of this like
loom.ext, text, but that's not really a
thing that matters in the world. We took
this and then we exposed it to our MCP
via some tools. One is a search docs
tool and one is a git docs tool that
basically allows you to find the
relevant documentation and pull it down.
And we did this in the context of like,
oh, we actually want to build some
agents that will help you instrument
code and it doesn't really really if you
can make docs work. Um, but we're also
running an experiment like could we do
this for internal development where we
can make our docs available and it can
fetch the right information at the right
time with slightly less input from a
human. And I actually think those
investments are going to be very very
good
>> in terms of like again these going back
to the core things that make development
better is like we're building better
talks or better specs or something and
we actually have a reason to consume
them now. And so I would I would
definitely invest in those kinds of
things. But again, I think the your your
results are going to be super anecdotal
and and not scientific and you know, if
you will, you like vibe check these
things. I I hate that terminology for
words, but like there is no better
analogy. Like you actually don't know if
it's better or worse on vibes. Yeah, it
is. It's not a great term, but it's
actually like a fairly great term and
like it's descriptive uh to what you're
doing. I guess I I guess kind of on that
uh on that note that's what I was going
to ask which is like how much uh do you
expect to see results and kind of real
world impact uh today versus uh how much
are we are you doing this out of
conviction of I'm building a muscle that
I think will be impactful not in three
years time but maybe in six months time
or 12 months time. So I think it spoke.
So there there
I I'll give you a real quick anecdote of
like why I think this is impactful
today. It has been for months. I started
off like when cursor had just started
and it was mostly just type ahead. I'm
like folks it's just type. not there's
no magic here. And I tried to and I
think that like composer, which is their
agent, was still very new. And I'm like,
okay, look, I'm going to try to not be
cynical. And I'm cynical by default
because like crypto bros and like the
whole internet is full of people
grifting all the time, right? And so
cynical by default is actually a totally
reasonable way to be in life. Um, but
I'm like, okay, I'll try it. I tried
cursor
>> and I went through a normal workflow. a
normal workflow in any in any company in
the world that if you are serious is
like I have an API or something like
that that looks the same as all the
other APIs I need to build another one
or I need to like I need to build
another thing that looks exactly the
same as all the other things right like
that is like software engineering in a
nutshell and so I'm like okay I did that
but I I tried to do it using composer
and stuff so I'm like okay I need to
build this here's here's an existing one
that you can model it off of and it
roughly did it and then I'm like okay
and I need to generate a test here's an
existing one and it roughly did it in
fact the test it did better than I would
do because it just it added additional
branches that I probably would not cover
just cuz I don't care because they're
like not you know exactly
>> less lazy than the developers.
>> Yeah. And but it was successful and it
was basically what I would have done. It
copy pasted the file. It changed a bunch
of stuff to match a new thing. That
would have been my flow and I'd roughly
time myself like how long this would
take me versus how long it took me to do
almost an identical task through this
and it was significantly faster. Like I
was able to get like two to three times
more output from that. That is not the
same as prompting cloud code to build
stuff for you to be clear.
>> That was me like using the agent to do
boiler plate working that and this is
months ago. That was already super
effective. The type ahead super
effective. So I think value's been there
already but it's a different thing. Um
but what I will tell you also is there
is a an sort of an implicit value that
is happening right now that is not
talked about as much. people like me,
uh, a couple founders that we acquired
the companies of that, uh, one one's
newer, but he's the same persona, I'm
sure, but, um, this one founder of
Century, his name's Inji,
got interested in this for a long time
at Century, he's been kind of, um,
managing teams, if you will, like kind
of like me at Century, not really
writing code for the company.
>> And this piqu his interest, as a lot of
us it is, and now he's back in the
weeds. He's building stuff and and
whatnot. that is not talked about as
much but that is like so unbelievably
important.
>> Yeah.
>> And you see this persona of people that
are builders that are curious about
technology like the core people in my
opinion that drive this industry are now
like backed in the weeds. They are
excited about change because for a long
time this industry has kind of been
stagnant. It's like the big companies
out in the world. There's not much you
can do about it. We solve most of the
hard problems in in all honesty. And so
I think that's like a really really
important thing. And a lot of this comes
from like this excitement and this
passion and whatnot which leads to like
genuine ROI in businesses because it
leads to thought I guess if you will. um
that that's that's like immeasurable in
my opinion and that's a really important
thing that you just got to enable people
to to dig into the technology and and
what it translates to for people like me
is like I will happily
>> my wife less happy about this for but I
will happily spend my evenings working
on random things because I'm like
actually excited about technology aid
you know and and again immeasurable but
like unbelievably important and and so I
think you get all of these things some
practical value right now today if
people understand how to use the tech
Okay.
>> Right.
>> And some sort of value that's hard to
really analyze from people sort of how
they think, how they make decisions.
>> Time more on the uh the deep thinking on
it that you might produce the same lines
of code like it's going to be hard to
doing it. They would just sort of be
better and maybe you also just
energized. Uh uh I think energized
>> would otherwise like uh be sort of a bit
tired of the grunt work. Uh
>> yeah, but I think it's also like you
have people in your company that make
decisions. Doesn't matter where they are
in the stack of your company, the more
they can see what is happening in the
world of like technology trends and
stuff, the better they're going to make
decisions period. That's just a source
of data, right? And this has always been
my strength at Century is like I am
always in the weeds. I will always have
strong signal out of data. Data is not
surveys and by the way. Data is
like me living the world. Um, and that
that's the value I see is like people
are like in the weeds again, which just
means they have better opinions. They
have taste. They have all these things
that are just like so so so important to
building like great products and great
companies. And so that is like the most
important thing about getting people
involved in using the technology. But
again, you can also get speed ups if you
just use it in a way that's rational. So
>> yeah. Yeah. Yeah. And you build those
out. I think uh well, there's like uh a
dozen more questions I want to ask you
about, but I think we're out of time. I
I'll ask one more sort of quick one uh
uh for the broader audience here. um you
know we've kind of gone from your
practices to sort of development teams
as a whole and how do you build them for
the individual right if you're if you're
a developer out there uh and you're you
know you see the transformation to your
own profession happening I guess what's
the what's the primary tip that you
would uh give someone uh in this state
right like what's a what's to uh to like
do or don'ts uh uh uh to uh adapt.
>> I would just say embrace it. Embrace it.
It's fair to be skeptical. Don't listen
to everything on the internet. Don't
listen to any CEOs of of big companies
that are like spewing out nonsense. Um
but yeah, just embrace it. Like it's not
it's not removing engineering or any
hogwash that's going on in the world.
Like I do just as much engineering now
as before, if not more. But just embrace
it. Like you can't ignore it. If you
ignore it, you're you're dead. like dead
in the water from a career point of
view, from a company point of view. You
can't ignore anything that's happening
right now. I think that's evident with
how every single company in the world
has shifted in this direction and they
are very smart people running those
companies. So, but yeah, just embrace
it. Embrace it. Find a way to like spend
time using the technology. Ideally, you
can do it for work. If not, maybe find a
job where you can. I'm not sure. So, but
yeah.
>> Yeah. No, good uh good tip. Very aligned
with my uh view on it. you know, you
can't deny it and uh you need to build
up the muscle even if you're not feeling
the return of it uh uh immediately. Um
hey David, thanks uh thanks again for
all the uh the insights, the learnings
uh of it. Uh looking forward to uh
continuing to hear your opinions. I love
the sort of the uh the sound bites and
such uh you put out on uh on the social
media and uh and the conversations of
it. Uh and yeah, there's a you know
pioneering space. So keep on doing it
and uh looking forward to to hearing
more learnings.
>> Yeah. Awesome.
>> And thanks everybody for tuning in and I
hope you join us for the next one.
[Music]